Mary van Kleeck Papers, 1849-1998
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES1906-1961
  - Articles, reprints, and published statements, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation; Oversize Materials]
    - "Employment Statistics and Trade Unions," American FederationistApr. 1927 (Box 34)
    - "The Club's Organization," [written for Women's City Club Bulletin]4 May 1927 (Box 34)
    - "Measuring Employment in a Municipality," National Municipal ReviewMay 1927 (Box 34)
    - "How the United States Can Aid the International Labor Organization Through Research," American Labor Legislation ReviewJune 1927 (Box 34)
    - "Financial Incentives: An Inseparable Part of the Task of Management," Taylor SocietyJune 1927 (Box 34)
    - "How to Manage," The VolunteerAug. 1927 (Box 34)
    - "What Will You Do Next?," American FederationistSept. 1927 (Box 34)
    - "Behind the Scenes in Candy Factories," Life and Labor BulletinMay 1928 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - "Unemployment in Passaic," Department of Worker's Education, May 1928 (Box 34)
    - "A Plan for the Survey of the Teaching of the Social Sciences," Smith Alumnae QuarterlyMay 1928 (Box 34)
    - "Recent Gains in Industrial Relations," The World TomorrowMay 1928 (Box 34)
    - "Labor and Institutions for Social Research," The Journal of Electrical Workers and OperatorsSept. 1928 (Box 34)
    - "Cambridge, England Conference of the International Industrial Relations Association," [written for Women's City Club Magazine]9 Nov. 1928 (Box 34)
    - "Beziehungen Zwischen Sozialer Forschung und Sozialer Arbeit in den Vereinigten Staaten," Slätter des Deutschen Roten Kreuzes 1928 (Box 34)
    - "Social Research and Industry, ProgressJan.-Mar. 1929 (Box 34)
    - "Shall We Count the Unemployed?," Graphic SurveyApr. 1929 (Box 34)
    - "Unemployment and the Census," Engineering and Mining Journal18 May 1929 (Box 34)
    - "Human Relations in a Scientific Organization of Industry," Factory and Industrial ManagementOct. 1929 (Box 34)
    - "Social Research in Industry," 1929 (Box 34)
    - "Human Relations in the Scientific Organization of Work," Fourth International Congress on Scientific Organization of Work 1929 (Box 34)
    - "Die Weltwirtschaftliche Grundlegung für Bestgestaltung der Arbeit in Betrieben," Neue Nachbarschaft, Jan. 1930 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - "A French Labor Leader Interpret Scientific Management," [written for Bulletin of the Taylor Society]13 Feb. 1930 (Box 34)
    - "At Filene's: Vicissitudes in the Share of Employes in Management," Graphic SurveyFeb. 1930 (Box 34)
    - "America's Unemployment Puzzle," [written for North American Review]17 Mar. 1930 (Box 34)
    - "Employment or Unemployment-That is the Question," American Labor Legislation ReviewMar. 1930 (Box 34)
    - "The Art Workshop: For the Art of Living," Smith Alumnae QuarterlyMay 1930 (Box 34)
    - "The College Settlement: Forerunner of the Art Workshop," in The Art Workshop-The First Year, 1929-1930circa 1930 (Box 34)
    - "The Federal Unemployment Census of 1930," American Statistical AssociationMar. 1931 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - "Toward a National Employment Service," The Survey15 Apr. 1931 (Box 34)
    - "A Blow to Labor," [written for The Survey]23 Mar. 1931 (Box 34)
    - "Social Economic Planning in the U.S.S.R.," preface to America Reprint of Report Prepared for the 1931 World Social Economic Congress30 Oct. 1931 (Box 34)
    - "Planning and the World Paradox," Survey GraphicNov. 1931 (Box 34)
    - Le Congrès D'Aménagement Économique et Social, Bulletin International du Service SocialDec. 1931 (Box 34)
    - "The Personnel Manager in the World Workshop," The Personnel JournalDec. 1931 (Box 34)
    - "Social Planning and Social Work," [written for Survey Graphic]12 Jan. 1932 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - "Planning to End Unemployment," Survey GraphicMar. 1932 (Box 34)
    - "The Task of a Trustee," Smith Alumnae QuarterlyMay 1932 (Box 34)
    - "Changes Toward Social Control: What Have We Done About the Social Ideals?," The Woman's PressJuly 1932 (Box 34)
    - "A Planned Economy As a National Economic Objective for Social Work," The CompassMay 1933 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - "Scientific Management in the Second Five Year Plan," Soviet Russia TodayJune 1933 (Box 34)
    - "Prosperity Through Scarcity: The Status of the Workers Under the NRA," Common SenseSept. 1933 (Box 34)
    - "NIRA versus PIATILETKA: Can Capitalism Plan?," Soviet Russia TodaySept. 1933 (Box 34)
    - "Comrade Conductor to the Intellectuals of America," [written for Soviet Russia Today]16 Nov. 1933 (Box 34)
    - "Dictatorships and Democracy," Soviet Russia TodayNov. 1933 (Box 34)
    - "Racial Conflict and Economic Competition: Some Observations on Hitlerism," Feb. 1934 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - "Economic Security for the Professional," The Bulletin for the Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists and TechniciansFeb. 1934 (Box 35)
    - "Should Social Workers Unionize?," Better Times12 Mar. 1934 (Box 35)
    - "An Open Letter from Mary van Kleeck," Social Work TodayMar. 1934 (Box 35)
    - "Common Goals of Labor And Social Work," Social Work TodayMay 1934 (Box 35)
    - "Inter-Professional Action for Social Insurance," The Monthly ReviewJune 1934 (Box 35)
    - "Our Illusions Regarding Government," The SurveyJune 1934 (Box 35)
    - "Women In Industry," [written for Encyclopaedia of the Social Sciences], July 1934 (Box 35)
    - "The Workers' Bill For Unemployment and Social Insurance," New Republic12 Nov. 1934 (Box 35)
    - "Security for Americans IV: The Workers' Bill for Unemployment and Social Insurance," The New Republic12 Dec. 1934 (Box 35)
    - "Social Workers and Social Security," Better Times7 Jan. 1935 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "What Price Unemployment Insurance?, Common SenseFeb. 1935 (Box 35)
    - "Interprofessional Co-Operation for Social Security," [written for American Federation of Teachers]10 Aug. 1935 (Box 35)
    - "A Planned Economy," Soviet Russia TodayNov. 1935 (Box 35)
    - "Trade-Union Methods for Social Workers," [written for Social Work Today]16 Dec. 1935 (Box 35)
    - "Sources of Power for the Social Work Program: Do We Need a Labor Party?," Social Work TodayDec. 1935 (Box 35)
    - "An Outline of Principles As Submitted to a Committee of Social Workers," Unemployment Insurance Review 1935 (Box 35)
    - "The Social Challenge to University Women," Journal of the American Association of University WomenJan. 1936 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - "United Action for Social Security," [written for the New Masses]27 Mar. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "Labor Laws for Women," The Woman TodayMar. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "National Economic Backgrounds for Interracial Cooperation," Spelman MessengerMay 1936 (Box 35)
    - "Today's Challenge to the Professions: The People's Needs and the Coming Elections," IPA News BulletinSept. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "In Defense of Social Work Principles," Social Work Today6 Oct. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "I am Supporting the American Labor Party…," [written for The New Republic]21 Oct. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "I Vote for the Labor Party," The Witness29 Oct. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "What I Expect of Roosevelt," The Nation, 14 Nov. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "Inter-Professional Action," The Screen GuildDec. 1936 (Box 35)
    - "The Women's Charter," The Woman TodayFeb. 1937 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - "The Future of American Minorities," The Friend29 July 1937 (Box 35)
    - "Soviet Planning," Soviet Russia TodayNov. 1937 (Box 35)
    - "Economic Orientation of the Professions in the United States," [written for Futuro]19 Sept. 1938 (Box 35)
    - "Trade Unions and Soviet Security," Soviet Russia TodayNov. 1938 (Box 35)
    - "Comment for Christian Science Monitor on the problem of Jewish refugees in the United States," 29 Dec. 1938 (Box 35)
    - "Industrial Democracy and World Peace," Church League of Industrial Democracy Monthly BulletinFeb. 1939 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - "What is Fascism?," Smith Alumnae QuarterlyAug. 1939 (Box 35)
    - Unidentified fragment circa Autumn 1939 (Box 35)
    - "Postscript on Finland," Social Work Today27 Dec. 1939 (Box 35)
    - "World Democracy Needs the Soviet Union," Soviet Russia TodayOct. 1940 (Box 35)
    - "Social Work in the World Crisis," in Social Work, Peace and the People's Well-Being 1941 (Box 35)
    - "What Christianity Requires," The Witness1 May 1941 (Box 35)
    - "Resources for Life," The Witness, 8 May 1941 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and the War," The Witness, 15 May 1941 (Box 35)
    - "Prisoner Number 60140: A Social Case Record," The Witness16 Apr. 1942 (Box 35)
    - "Labor's Contribution to Production," American Labor Legislative ReviewJune 1942 (Box 35)
    - "Technology Challenges Women's Education," Pi Lambda Theta JournalMar. 1943 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "The Beveridge Plan For Child and Teacher, Progressive EducationApr. 1943 (Box 35)
    - "British Plan for Social Security," Lawyer's Guild ReviewJan.-Feb. 1943 (Box 35)
    - "A Soviet Woman to an American Woman," Soviet Russia TodayMay 1943 (Box 35)
    - "After the Strikes-What?," The Witness8 July 1943 (Box 35)
    - "Labor Relations in the U.S. Coal Industry," Public Affairs, Autumn 1943 (Box 35)
    - "The New Promise of American Life," Pi Lambda Theta Journal, Dec. 1943 (Box 35)
    - "Community Organizations for Post-War Employment," [Unpublished]4 Feb. 1944 (Box 35)
    - "Women Workers," Mechanical EngineeringFeb. 1944 (Box 35)
    - "The Soviets and the New Technology," Survey GraphicFeb. 1944 (Box 35)
    - "Planning and Reconstruction," U.S.S.R. in Reconstruction, 26 May 1944 (Box 35)
    - "Social Work on the Industrial Frontier," The CompassNov. 1944 (Box 35)
    - Statement on the position of the Society for the Advancement of Management in the Current Labor-Management Crisis, News Bulletin, Jan. 1946 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - "Soviet Reconstruction," Soviet Russia TodayMay 1946 (Box 35)
    - "Introduction," SyntheseMay-June 1946 (Box 35)
    - "Our Unsocial Foreign Policy," STAFFMay 1947 (Box 35)
    - "Today's Imperialism," Bulletin of the Society of the Catholic CommonwealthSpring 1947 (Box 35)
    - "Atomic Energy: Opportunity for International Cooperation," Soviet Russia TodayAug. 1947 (Box 35)
    - "Changing Economic Structure: As Affecting Relations Between the United States and the Soviet Union," Bulletin of the Society of the Catholic Commonwealth23 Nov. 1947 (Box 35)
    - "Food Without Politics for Europe," Super-EgoFeb. 1948 (Box 35)
    - "The Technological Basis for National Development and Its Implications for International Development: A Statement of Guiding Principles for Study of Resources for Optimum Living Standards," 1948 (Box 35)
    - "Disarmament for Social Needs," Swords into PlowsharesJan. 1949 (Box 35)
    - "Social Change for Human Needs: Today's Christian Imperative," Tunkhannock, Pennsylvania: Episcopal Church Publishing CompanyDec. 1951 [2 typed drafts] (Box 35)
    - "Christianity and Atomic Energy: Appeals to End Bomb Tests," The Witness16 Feb. 1956 (Box 35)
    - "Christianity and Atomic Energy: International Effort to Ban Weapons," The Witness23 Feb. 1956 (Box 35)
    - "Christianity and Atomic Energy: Obstacles to International Agreement," The Witness1 Mar. 1956 (Box 35)
    - "Christianity and Atomic Energy: For Peace Only," The Witness8 Mar. 1956 (Box 35)
    - "Peace Through International Trade In A Changing World," Public Ownership in the United StatesMay 1961 (Box 35)
    - "World Trade and National Liberation," Worldwide Trade for Peace: An Appeal for International Economic Unity 1964 (Box 35)
    - "Democracy in a Co-operative Society," Progressive Education Booklet, no. 1undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - "The Federal Unemployment Census of 1930," Mar. supplement of the American Statistical Journalundated (Box 35)
    - "Social Research and Industry," n.p.undated (Box 35)
  - Short stories 1904, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute-Conferences; Oversize Materials]
    - List of speeches given 1910-17 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - "Industrial Citizenship for Women," notes, Women's City Club, Cincinnati30 Nov. 1918 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - "Women in Hazardous Occupations," notes, Safety Congress, Syracuse3 Dec. 1918 (Box 35)
    - "Women's Invasion of Industry and Changes in Protective Standards," notes, Annual Meeting, American Academy of Political Science, Columbia University6 Dec. 1918 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Women's Trade Union League, Washington, D.C.16 Dec. 1918 (Box 35)
    - "Women Workers in the Period of Reconstruction," notes, Annual Meeting, American Association for Labor Legislation, Richmond, Virginia28 Dec. 1918 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Congressional Women's Club, Washington, D.C.3 Jan. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Home Work and Industrial Work," notes, Department of Agriculture, State Relations Group, Washington, D.C.4 Dec. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled speech, U.S. Employment Service Luncheon, Washington, D.C.14 Jan. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Annual Meeting, Consumers' League of Eastern Pennsylvania, Philadelphia22 Jan. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Conference of Committee on Women in Industry, Columbus, Ohio27 Jan. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Opening of Conference in Indianapolis on Woman in Industry Service28 Jan. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "College Women and the Labor Problem," notes, Smith College Club, Washington, D.C.11 Feb. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Women in Industry," notes, U.S. Employment Service15 Feb. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Maryland Equal Suffrage Association, Baltimore16 Feb. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Women in Labor," notes, Conference on Problems of Negro Labor, Washington, D.C.17 Feb. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "National and Local Standards for Women's Work," notes, Business Women's Club, Lexington, KY8 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Conference of Social Workers, Louisville, KY10 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Annual Meeting, Consumer's League, Louisville, KY10 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Meeting at Young Women's Christian Association, Minneapolis, MN14 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Suffragists and Industrial Democracy," Jubilee Convention of the National American Woman Suffrage Association, St. Louis, MOMar. 1919, printed by National Woman's Suffrage Publishing Company, Inc. (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Mass meeting, Duluth, MN16 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "The College and the Labor Problem," notes, Smith College, Northampton, MA21 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Civic Club of Allegheny County, Pittsburgh26 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Future of Women in Industry," notes, Women's City Club, Cleveland31 Mar. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Political and Industrial Position of Women, notes, Men's Bible Class, Church of the Covenant6 Apr. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "The Changes in Attitude Toward Women in Industry Because of the War," notes, Hibernian Hall mass meeting8 Apr. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Work of Woman in Industry Service Regarding Negro Women Wage-Earners," Zion Hall8 Apr. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "The Changes in Social Life and in the Position and Responsibility of Women Worked by the Close of the War," notes, Ashley Hall, Chapel exercises, Charleston, SC9 Apr. 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Federal Employe's Union Quarterly Meeting, Local No. 2, 18 Apr. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "The New Spirit in Industry," Toledo Consumers League3 May 1919, printed by Toledo Consumers League (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Fortnightly Club, Summit, NJ7 May 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Women's Part in Reconstruction," notes, Annual Meeting, Interstate Industrial Arts Association, Washington, DC10 May 1919 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Women Voters' League, Conference on Labor, Washington, DC19 May 1919 (Box 35)
    - "The New Industrial Position of Women," DetroitOct. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "The Task of Working Women in the International Congress," First International Congress of Working Women, Washington, DCOct. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "Women in Industry," notes, Women's Alliance, Unity Congregational Society, Mount Morris Baptist Church19 Dec. 1919 (Box 35)
    - "The Democratic Spirit in Industry," introduction to four speeches 1920 (Box 35)
    - "Relation of the Young Women's Christian Association to the Problems of Labor," YWCA Convention, Cleveland 1920 (Box 35)
    - "The Responsibility of the Church for Unemployment," Conference on Unemployment of the Clergy of the Diocese of New York20 Nov. 1921 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - "Economic Reasons for Women in Industry Laws," taken from speech given to National Federation of Business and Professional Women's ClubsJan. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Labor Laws and Opportunities for Women," National Convention of Business and Professional Women, July 1921, printed in Association MonthlyJan. 1922 (Box 35)
    - Untitled Statement on women working at night, Passaic, NJ10 Feb. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Industrial Basis of Social Work," Delaware Conference of Social Work17 Feb. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Industrial and Economic Problems," Consumers' League of DelawareFeb. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Industrial Basis for Social Work," Chicago Social Service Club14 Mar. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "The Relation of the Parish to Labor Problems," notes, St. Paul's Church, Paterson, NJ2 Apr. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Women in Industry," notes, The Women's Missionary Society, Pelham Manor, NY15 May 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Can Governmental Labor Bureaus Affect the Causes of Industrial Unrest?," Conference of Association of Government Labor Officials, Harrisonburg, PA24 May 1922 (Box 35)
    - Untitled Address, Mass Meeting of Trade Unions11 Sept. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Labor and the Community," Portland, OR11 Sept. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "The Moral Challenge of Industry," General Convention of the Protestant (Box 35)
    - Episcopal ChurchSept. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "What Contribution Has Our Church to Make to the Improvement of Human Relations in Industry," Sept. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and Industrial Relations," Berkeley Divinity School, Middletown, CT19 Nov. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "A Plan for the Collection of Current Periodic Statistics of Employment," Pennsylvania Conference on Administration of Labor Laws27 Nov. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "Children in an Industrial Community," notes, Englewood, NJ Women's Club4 Dec. 1922 (Box 35)
    - Untitled notes, Federation for Placement Work, Boston12 Dec. 1922 (Box 35)
    - "What Industry Means to Women in Industry," corrected transcript, Women's Industrial Conference, Washington, DC11 Jan. 1923 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - "Professional Standards in their Relation to Fundamentals in Social Work," notes, New York School of Social Work, New York14 Mar. 1923 (Box 35)
    - "Labor Legislation for Women," circa 1923 (Box 35)
    - "Changing Economic Position of Women," notes for course on "Modern Problems in the Light of Christian Conscience," New York Church Institute, New York21 Jan. 1924 (Box 35)
    - "Christian Approach to the Solution of Industrial Problems," notes, Church Congress, Boston1 May 1924 [also includes statement from press release] (Box 35)
    - "The Child Labor Amendment," Consumers' League of New York, Women's Civic Club, Utica, NY29 Oct. 1924 (Box 35)
    - Untitled remarks, Annual Business Meeting of the Taylor Society4 Dec. 1924 (Box 35)
    - "Child Labor Amendment," notes, League of Women Voters, Short Hills, NJ9 Jan. 1925 (Box 35)
    - "Equal Rights Cannot be Won by Constitutional Amendment," 5 Feb. 1925 (Box 35)
    - Remarks in Honor of Mrs. Edward MacDowell, the first recipient of the Pictorial Review Annual Achievement Award, National Arts Club28 Feb. 1925 (Box 35)
    - Remarks on the Fiftieth Anniversary of Flushing High School14 May 1925 (Box 35)
    - "What Industry Can Do to Raise Standards of Work for Women," Conference on Women in Industry, Harrisburg, PA8 Dec. 1925: typed and printed copies (Box 35)
    - "Modern Industry and Society," Women's Industrial Conference, Women's Bureau, Department of Labor, Washington, DC19 Jan. 1926 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - "Justice: Towards a Solution of Our Social Problems," Annual Meeting of Association to Promote Proper Housing for Girls16 Feb. 1926 (Box 36)
    - "The Effect of Labor Laws Upon Women in Industry: A Problem for Investigation," Convention of Association of Governmental Labor Officials, Columbus, OH8 June 1926 (Box 36)
    - "The Necessity of Perfecting the Interview as a Method of Research," notes, Taylor Society, New York10 Dec. 1926 (Box 36)
    - Discussion of paper by Leifur Magnusson, "International Competition and Labor Standards," Joint Meeting of American Association for Labor Legislation and American Economic Association, St. Louis, MO28 Dec. 1926 (Box 36)
    - Remarks following presentation of paper by Elliott Dunlap Smith, "Financial Incentives," New York Metropolitan Section of the Taylor Society, New York14 Apr. 1927 (Box 36)
    - "Social Research and Industry," typed and printed, First International Conference of Social Work, Paris12 July 1928 (Box 36)
    - "The Economic Basis of World Peace," Walmer Road Baptist Church, Toronto, Canada13 Oct. 1929 (Box 36)
    - Discussion of Dr. Person's "The New Challenge to Scientific Management," (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Taylor SocietyDec. 1930 (Box 36)
    - "The Federal Unemployment Census of 1930," Joint meeting of the American Statistical Association and the American Association for Labor Legislation, Cleveland, OH30 Dec. 1930 (Box 36)
    - "Unemployment Insurance," notes, American Association of Social Workers10 Feb. 1931 (Box 36)
    - Untitled remarks, National Social Work CouncilApr. 1931 (Box 36)
    - "Employment Statistics," Annual Meeting of the Association of Governmental Officials in Industry, Boston20 May 1931 (Box 36)
    - "When and How Should This Be Done?," Department of Christian Social Service of the Protestant Episcopal Church, Conference of Social Workers, Milwaukee22 June 1931 (Box 36)
    - "Introductory Address," International Industrial Relations Association, AmsterdamAug. 1931 (Box 36)
    - "The New Significance of Standards of Living," Women's Trade Union League, Bryn Mawr College5 Dec. 1931: typed press release6 Dec. 1931; printed in Bryn Mawr Alumnae BulletinFeb. 1932 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - "Unemployment and the Banks," Mid-Atlantic division of the ABW, New York, 18 Dec. 1931; printed, A.B.W. News, Jan. 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Social Economic Planning," Foundation for the Advancement of the Social Sciences of the University of Denver, Denver20 Feb. 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Community Planning to End Unemployment," City Club, Denver3 Feb. 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Security of Employment: The Objective for Labor's Program," Organized Labor's Council of Action of the Rocky Mountain States14 Mar. 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Changes Toward Social Control," transcript, Biennial Convention of the National YWCA, Minneapolis6 May 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Social Planning and Social Work," Division V of the National Conference of Social Work21 May 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Economic Planning and Social Control," opening session of Bryn Mawr Summer School, Bryn Mawr College, Bryn Mawr, PA11 June 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Opening Remarks," Second International Conference of Social Work11 July 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Closing Remarks," Second International Conference of Social Work14 July 1932 (Box 36)
    - "Report of Round Table Meetings," notes, Church League for Industrial Democracy, Executive Committee Meeting21 Feb. 1933 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - "Soviet American Trade Relations," notes, New School for Social Research23 Mar. 1933 (Box 36)
    - Untitled remarks, National Women's Trade Union League annual meeting27 Mar. 1933 (Box 36)
    - Untitled notes, Council of Social Agencies, Philadelphia28 Mar. 1933 (Box 36)